<Versions>
<Current>
<v3>
Now covers:
	Moon and Star (52397)
	Osare Culort Armor -UNP (43609)
	Daedra of Coldharbour (51596)

Blocklist:

Exclusions:

Fixes:

Changes:

Additions:

Balancing:
	Sabre speed increased from 0.85 to 1.05 reach increased from 0.85 to 0.9.
	Scimitar reach increased from 0.95 to 1.0.

Renamed:

Updated Patches:

New Patches:
	Daedra of Coldharbour
</v3>
</Current>

<Old>
<v2.6.1>
Now covers:
	The Loners Sword (16751) The two-hand version needs to be renamed 'Loner's Greatsword'
	Axe of Hrothmund (31116)
	Much Ado about Snow Elves - A Tragedy - Act I (16455)
	Breton Knight (59544)
	The Hanging Gardens - a Quest(30279)
	Seadog Pirate Armor (20911)

Blocklist:
	ItBeatsForHer.esp

Exclusions:
	Enchanting/Distribution exclusions on Conan Hyborian age weapons previously missed.

Fixes:
	Corrected a flag that prevented Iron Arrows from being picked up in the world. (N2T)
	Added some keywords I had missed before. (SiC)
	Corrected a typo in Silver Ingot recipes that caused it to hide when the Gold and Silver perk was taken. (CCOR)
	The Wyrmstooth patch was incorrectly credited to the wrong user, Velgath made it.
	Sorted masters. (Wyrm)

Additions:
	Added a new Disparity version of the Wind Destruction patch.
	Added new patches for aMidianborn Content Addon to correct a few enchanted armors names. (aMidCA)
	Added proper bindings for 'Ancient Nord' and 'Honed Ancient Nord'/'Ancient Nord Honed' weapons.

Renamed:
	Orcish Bow (Legendry) -> Orcish Bow (Legendary) (N2T)
	Vindskjær -> Vindskjaer (N2T) for real this time.

Updated Patches:
	Nock to Tip (N2T)
	Immersive Creatures (SiC)
	Compelete Crafting Overhaul (CCOR)
	Wyrmstooth patch (Wyrm)

New Patches:
	Wind Destruction.esp (Disparity version)
	aMidianborn Content Addon Patches (aMid CA)
</v2.6.1>
<v2.6>
Now covers:
	Sovereign Slayer (57363)
	True Thief Armor (38409)

Blocklist:
	Throwing_Weapons_Redux.esp

Exclusions:
	Removed overreaching distribution exclusions on Dawnguard and Dagonborn Books.

Fixes:
	Corrected a broken keyword on Thalmor Cloths. (WAFR CCOR patch)
	Corrected a broken Enchantment link on The Forgemasters Fingers. (WAFR CCOR patch)
	Corrected a weapon modifier that was making all Greatswords stronger than intended.
	Corrected a double binding for 'Ash' weapons.

Changes:
	Changed material keyword on 'Colovian Composite Bow' and 'Colovian Dark Composite Bow' to sort them in the wood category. (IW)
	Reduced Bound weapon costs and spells can now be randomly learned from Studies perks. (BA)

Additions:
	New binding for Ash Spawn weapons from Dragonborn.
	Added clothing keyword all clothing items so they will sort to the Clothing category and be recognized as clothing. (IA)
	Adjusted summoning spells and summoned NPCs to PerMa standards. (SiC)
	Wyrmstooth patch to adjust spells and summoned creatures to PerMa standards and can be learned randomly when taking the Studies perks. (Wyrm)
	Cure Poison and Cure Disease Spell Tomes will now teach the PerMa spell. (Wyrm)

Balancing:
	Slightly reduced Mace and Spiked Mace damage. (13 -> 10/11)
	Slightly increased Club and Spiked Club damage. (9 -> 10/11)
	Slightly reduced Morning Star damage. (14 -> 12)
	Increased armor of 'Stormcloak Officer' to be better than normal 'Stormcloak'.

Updated Patches:
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR Patch (WAFR CCOR)
	Immersive Weapons (IW)
	Immersive Armors (IA)
	Bound Armory (BA)
	Skyrim Immersive Creatures (SiC)

New Patches:
	Wyrmstooth - PerMa Patch.esp (Wyrm)
</v2.6>
<v2.5.3>
Now covers:
	Albion Swords - The Chieftain (58257)
	Albion Swords - The Cluny (58630)
	Albion Swords - The Sherwood (58374)
	Albion The Baron (56438) (Two-Hand version needs name changed to 'The Great Baron)
	The Vassal (56785)
	Mithrodin Sword (23085)

Exclusions:
	Several secondary spells will no longer improperly have a scroll made. (PerMa)
	Tightened up distribution exclusions for Dragon Priest weapons.

Fixes:
	Corrected description of Vokun Circlet in CCOR patches
	Corrected Invisible Vampire Lord form bug that got put into the WAFR patches also.
	Corrected masters on WAFR patch. USKP was added for a test and I forgot to remove it.
	Corrected a typo that made light Dawnguard armors heavy.
	Removed a faulty Book exclusion that prevented many Illusion spells from being added to merchant chests and loot tables.

Additions:
	Added Enchanting and Language updates for changes made to newest version of Wintermyst.
	Added some more French to Languages.xml

Renamed:
	'Vindskjær' -> 'Vindskjaer' PaMa can't read Nordic. (N2T)
	'Forsworn Bow' -> 'Forsworn Bow (Improved)' (N2T)

Updated Patches:
	WAFR
	CCF
	Nock to Tip (N2T)
</v2.5.3>
<v2.5.2>
Now covers:
	Draconic Bloodline (51401) v1.1
	Mord Sith Cara Armor (50930)
	Deadly Trio (37746)
	Gallery of Armor (49827) v1.5a
	Lords Mail - Armor and Quest (40497)
	Knight Of Thorns Armor And Spear of Thorns (18940)
	aMidianborn Content Addon (24909) v1.9
	
Exclusions:
	DLC1ClothesVampireLordRoyalArmor and DLC1ClothesVampireLordArmor (Vampire Lord form skins) can no longer be enchanted or distributed.

Fixes:
	Removed some extra keywords from PerMa added Silver weapons. (WAFR)
	Added missing WAFR keywords to PerMa added SkyForge Steel weapons. (WAFR)
	Corrected a typo on binding for Rikke's Longbow that prevented it from patching correctly.
	Wind Destruction patch now has PerMa_Mage as a master, the Destruction tree would be messed up if PerMa_Mage was not used.
	Changed Spell Tomes to Book/Tome type to have the correct icon in SkyUI. (WDM)

Changes:
	Shield of Solitude changed to Light to match WAFR.

Additions:
	"Spear" added to Languages.xml
	"Explodes upon impact, dealing 2 points of poison damage per second for 20 seconds." added to Languages.xml

Updated Patches:
	CCF
	WAFR
	Wind Destruction.esp (Changes in included Readme)

New Patches:
	Nock2Tip.esp (updated by Force70)
	Unique Uniques.esp
</v2.5.2>
<v2.5.1>
Updated Patches:
	Quick fix for script version data error in CCOR patches.
</v2.5.1>
<v2.5>
Now covers:
	Rough Leather Armor (54672)
	Hunter Archer Armor (43649) English Translation (43873)
	Diverse Bows (59224)
	Grace Darklings Ranger Armor v3 (7184)

Fixes:
	Fixed a typo I made in PerMa Fixes.esp that made the Apprentice Destruction perks "+15% damage for next destruction spell" only work on apprentice destruction spells.
	LLs updated to better match WAFR (IW)
	Immersive Armors will no longer tell CCOR that Immersive Weapons is installed.
	My custom "Leather Strip to Leather" recipes had bad conditions that made them not properly upgrade to the "good" version. (WAFR)
		5 Strips makes 1 Leather while Smithing skill is below 50.
		4 Strips makes 1 Leather while Smithing skill is 50 or more and the Material: Leather perk is taken.
		25 Strips makes 5 Leather while Smithing skill is below 50.
		21 Strips makes 5 Leather while Smithing skill is 50 or more and the Material: Leather perk is taken.
		Values are based on the CCOR "Leather to Strips" recipes to use more strips than made by that recipe so there isn't an "infinite experience loop"

Changes:
	Lockpick recipe will require Inventor perk in Dexterity or the Wax Key perk in Lockpicking. (CCOR)
	Will now be in the "Tools and Materials" section of the crafting menu and can be hidden with the ToolRecipe toggle (CCOR);
	Crossbow Modification Kit (WAFR)
	Lockpick recipe (WAFR) (May conflict with other mods that edit Lockpick record weight/keywords)
	
	Now require the "Material: Gold and Silver" perk;
	Gold and Silver Ingots 
	Jewellery recipes that didn't already. (CCOR)
	Gem cutting recipes.
	Silver Sword and Greatsword recipes. (CCOR)
	Silver Gilded Crusader's Sword and Silver Crusader's Sword (CCOR)
	
	Now require the "Material: Leather" perk;
	Bandoliers Bags and Pouches (CCOR)

Additions:
	Included CCOR script "CCO_SubCraftingArmor" in the unmerged WAFR patch so my "Leather Strip to Leather" recipes will act right. It is an unedited copy of the script, if you use any CCOR variant you won't get the script (since CCOR already added it)
	Non-Iron, non-Fur, and non-Hide Breakdown recipes now require the Meltdown perk. (CCOR)

Balancing:
	Lowered fArmorRatingMax (NPC armor multiplier variable) from *2.5 to *2
	Reduced base damage and speed of Daggers by 0.5, should help resolve an issue where NPCs use daggers even with better, more appropriate, weapons in their inventory.
	Reduced Tanto base speed by 0.02.

Renamed:
	Horker Bow -> Horker Shortbow (GHWP)
	Dukes Longsword -> Dukes Greatsword (IW)
	Regent's Longsword -> Regent's Greatsword (IW)
	Silver Honed Longsword -> Silver Honed Greatsword (IW)
	Wabba Jaxe -> Wabba Jaxe Halberd (IW)
	Warchief's Might -> Warchief's Halberd (IW)

Updated Patches:
	PerMa Fixes.esp
	WAFR patches updated to WAFR 5.1
	CCF patches updated to CCF 1.4
	CCOR patches updated to CCOR 1.6
	Immersive Armors (IA)
	Immersive Weapons (IW)
	Ghosu - Horker Weapon Pack (GHWP)

Removed Patches:
	Nock 2 Tip: Use patch by Force70 (63671) Is being reworked to be a replacer.
	Unique Uniques: Use patch by Old Nick (63111) It's a replacement esp also.
</v2.5>
<v2.4.4>
Now covers:
	zzjay's wardrobe (53442)
	Compound Bow Collection-Redux (58716)
	Lord Marshal and Steel Falcon (62865)
	Skyrim Sewers 4 (14351)
	Common Clothes (51813)
	Mage Armor - Cleric Chainmail Robes (54600)
	B-D-Y-E-B Shield Mod (34433) patch version only
	Medusa Drakul armors and Thanatos dragon (31229)
	Tembtra Thief Armor UNP - CBBE (59451)
	Schwertleite (19665)
	Demon Hunter Armor v3 (42169)
	Jethead Armors (25636)
	Silver Dragon Armor (18028)

Blocklist:
	KWTelescope.esp
	GypsyEyesCaravan.V.2.esp

Fixes:
	Corrected an improperly attached script property that prevented Studies: Apprentice Destruction from granting a spell. (WAFR)
	Fist weapon damage scaling reduced by 50% for Khajiit. (WAFR)
	Corrected Thalmor Glass binding (aMidianborn)

Additions:
	Added masquerade bindings for Dawnguard
	Added masquerade keywords for Thalmor clothings. (WAFR and CCF)

Updated Patches:
	CCF: Keyword adjustments.
	WAFR: Fixes listed above.

New Patches:
	BDYEB.esp (See changelog in Data/Readmes)
	Unique Uniques.esp (Carried over some WAFR changes for consistency)
</v2.4.4>
<v2.4.3>
Fixes:
	Horker weapons and armor will now sort to Bonemold and not MISC. (GHWP)

Changes:
	Corsair's Sword will now bind as a Sabre not an Arming Sword. (Jswords)
	Horker weapons and armor recipes now require one or more Horker Tusk in your inventory to show. (GHWP)
	Honed Horker weapons and armor now require you to know how to make Improved Bonemold. (GHWP)
	Removed localization from the three WAFR patches as it was being a poo-poo head.
	Torch, Stone and Riekling Arrows/Bolts will no longer have variants made.

Additions:
	Weapon Modifiers for (Broken), (Damaged), (Worn), (Used), (Solid) and (Reliable). Primarily affects Frostfall.
	Several new Ammo materials added, mainly duplicate versions of existing materials, but with multiply set to false.

Updated Patches:
	1nivWICCloaks.esp (WiC) Removed Clothing keywords from two Leather helms I missed.
	Ghosu - Horker Weapon Pack.esp (GHWP) Added Longbows and adjusted LLs to match WAFR.
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR BOYD Patch.esp actually corrected name of NPCs Ma'jhad and Ra'zhinda. Removed localization
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR Patch.esp Removed localization
	Pre PaMa WAFR Patch.esp Removed localization
</v2.4.3>
<v2.4.2>
Now covers:
	Avatar of Grenth (23165)
	Kur0us Ebony Morning Star(22735)

Fixes:
	Corrected bad condition on Leather Strips to Leather recipe (WAFR, WAFR CCOR, WAFR CCOR BOYD)
	Corrected name of NPCs Ma'jhad and Ra'zhinda. (WAFR CCOR BOYD)

Changes:
	Updated installer so NMM users are not forced to add an unneeded patch when selecting the WAFR CCOR BOYD merged patch option.
</v2.4.2>
<v2.4.1>
Updated Patches:
	Pre PaMa WAFR Patch
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR Patch
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR BOYD Patch
</v2.4.1>
<v2.4>
Now covers:
	Evil Mastermind Armor (25476)
	Konahriks Accoutrements - Dragon Priest Armory (32458)
	Skyrim Knights (28044)

Blocklist:
	Combat Evolved.esp
	SkyTweak.esp

Exclusions:
	Gharol's Iron Sword can no longer be Reforge and will not have enchanted variants made or distributed.
	The 'Spellbreaker' shield can no longer be Reforged or Warforged.

Fixes:
	Corrected typo on bindings for Black Mage Hood (L) and Black Mage Mantled Hood (L) (Black Mage Armor)
	Corrected typo on bindings for Morgul Blade and Elven Short Blade (LOTR)
	The Azincourt (1H) is now bound to Longsword, The Azincourt remains a Bastard Sword
	Falmer armor and Imperial Helmet will now properly be tagged Heavy armor (SIC)
	Falmer shaman armor will now properly be tagged Light armor (SIC)
	Correct impact data set and block material on several SIC shields
	Imperial Tattered Armor, Dwarven Light Armor and Ancient Nord Light Gauntlets are now Light. (SIC)
	Corrected Palrada Plate, Scion Plate, Eternal Centurion, Rysio, Cyasmic and Shadow Fang bindings (TERA Armors)
	Dawnguard Ebony Shield now have original ebony shield armor rating (CCOR)
	Clothing cultist robes, gloves and boots now have missing masquerade cultist keyword (CCF, WAFR)
	Reinforced, Fitted gauntlets and boots now have missing masquerade stormcloak keyword (FALSKAAR)
	Fur Guard's gauntlets and boots, Eastmarch Guard's Helmet and Gloves of the Pugilist now have missing masquerade stormcloak keyword
	Shellbug Helmet now have missing falmer masquerade keyword
	Carius armor now have missing imperial masquerade keyword
	Fur Kilt and Fur Kilt with Mantle now have missing bandit masquerade keyword
	Fur Gauntlets and Boots now have only stormcloak masquerade keyword (bandit keyword removed)
	Fur Pant Armor now have missing bandit masquerade keyword (SIC)
	Masquerade keywords on Stormcloak, Imperial, Forsworn, Falmer, Vampire Circlets and Ulfric's Gag are removed.
	Masquerade keywords on Imperial and Falmer Shields are removed
	Added missed model to Ancient Nord Helmet (SIC)
	Damaged Ceremonial Armor now have broken armor stats (FALSKAAR)
	Corrected description of Silver Partisan. (WAFR)

Changes:
	Unenchanted, playable, Nightingale armor sets can now be Reforged and Warforged. Enchanted, non-playable, versions cannot.
	Changed Dragon Priest bindings back to WAFR (Vokun Silver>Steel, Otar Gold>Glass, Konahrik Dwarven>DragonPlate, Morokei Glass>Clothing, Dukaan NordicLight>StalhrimLight, Ahzidal ScaledHeavy>Ebony)
	Adjusted names of some Ancient Nord Armor to have better stats, Broken Ancient Nord Armor (Old)>Ancient Nord Armor (Broken). (SiC)
	Changed Hammer of Justice and Divine Hammer binding to BoundLow (FMR)

Additions:
	Moonbuckled, Neophyte, Cerulean Alchemist, Solace, Ebon Shroud and Eternal Magus bindings (TERA Armors)
	Merged DevilDukes NPC Armor Balance fixes into the WAFR patches to stop NPCs from hitting armor cap in Fur.
	WAFR patches will now have the Relev bash tag applied.

Balancing:
	Lowered base damage of Sabre from 12 to 11.
	Increased base damage of Scimitar from 11 to 12.
	Cutlass weapons will now bind to Sabre not Scimitar.
	New materials BoundLow(1.9) and BoundHigh(2.05).
	Increased Bone material damage from 0.25 to 0.9 (just above Wood)
	Increased Mammoth Bone material damage from 0.5 to 1.2
	New materials BoneHigh(0.95) and Mammoth BoneHigh(1.5).
	Giant Weapons Bleed increased to 3 from 2. Class changed from to Blunt_Blade from Blunt

Renamed:
	Ancient Nord Helmet -> Ancient Nord Light Helmet (WAFR, not playable)

Updated Patches:
	Immersive Armors: Bosmer Engraved set will now benefit from the Ebony perk and not the Glass perk.
	SiC: Name and keyword adjustments, added missed model
	CCOR, WAFR: Name and keyword adjustments
	CCF: Keyword adjustments.
	Wind Magic: Corrected Spell costs. Removed Update.esm and Dawnguard.esm as masters.
</v2.4>
<2.3.1>
Now covers:
	Spears By Soolie (62609)

Fixes:
	Winter is coming armor (Leather Snow Bear Claw, Leather Ornate and Leather Fancy Snow Bear Claw Hoods) will now have right armor rating.

Changes:
	"Spear" no longer binds to Partisan
	Zephyr is now a Shortbow

Additions:
	New weapon_type "Spear"; longer reach than Shortspear, higher damage, slower.
	New Ammo_type "Javelin"; Higer damage than Bolts, but heavier, slower and more affected by gravity.
	"Morgul blade", "Glamdring" and "Elven short blade" bindings (LOTR Weapons)
	Wolf Daito binding (IW)

Notes on Spears By Soolie:
	The Spear Patcher seems to be improperly marking a few random Spiked Clubs, Spiked Maces and Halberds as Spears, these need to be fixed by hand before running PaMa or you can end up with a ton of messed up weapons in your save. Run the Spear Patcher before PaMa, make sure to open the Spear Patch in TES5Edit and remove all weapon entries that are Spiked Club, Spiked Mace or Halberd before running PaMa. Due to the way Spears currently handles Spear distribution some Spears may not be as plentiful as intended. I've already contacted Soolie about these issues and plan to work with him/her to try to get it all worked out. The fixes I made for Spears my cause some conflicts with anything named Spear or Javelin that is not set up in a manor conducive to the Spears mods, if you find any please let me know so I can try to get them fixed.
</2.3.1>
<v2.3>
Now covers:
	Dragonbone Barbarian Armor (52711)
	Black Mage Armor (9645)
	Penobscot War Bow (61691)
	Skaal Heavy Armor (32126)
	Meridia's Secret Weapon - Two Handed Dawnbreaker (59703)
	Genesis Rhapsodos Rapier (19030)
	Luddemanns Armory (33213)
	Elven Electrum-Plated Equipment (62076)

Blocklist:
	zzEstrus.esp
	LootandDegradation.esp
	iNeed.esp
	WetandCold - Ashes.esp
	SoS - Civilization.esp
	dD - Enhanced Blood Main.esp
	Rainbows.esp
	Headtracking.esp
	Footprints.esp
	SplashofRain.esp
	ShootingStars.esp
	VioLens.esp
	Chesko_WearableLantern.esp

Fixes:
	Binding for Sigvatson Bow (Unique Bows)
	Typo on Stormcloak Mage Armor binding.
	Merta armor will now be Light.
	Corrected several bindings for Giant weapons added by SiC to fix 'Run Away!' bug.
	Corrected bindings for Colovian Composite Bow and Dark Colovian Composite Bow.
	Auriel's Shield, Shellbug Helmet, Falmer Circlet, Zahkriisos, Vokun and Rahgot are now Heavy
	Falskaar Reinforced, Tsun's boots, Ebony Light Mail, Dawnguard Rune Shield, Dukaan, Cultist Mask, Miraak (Light) and Otar Circlet are now Light
	Falmer armor will now properly be tagged Light armor.
	Winter is coming armor (Steel Snow Bear Claw, Steel Ornate and Steel Fancy Snow Bear Claw Hoods)  will now properly be tagged Heavy armor.
	Corrected EbonyLow, DwarvenLow, DwarvenHigh, HorkerHH, AdvancedLight armor values
	Corrected several weapon type bindings from 'Bastardsword' to 'Bastard Sword'. 'Basic Greatsword', 'Narsil - 2H', 'Anduril - 2H', and 'Claidhem' were affected.
	Patched Enhanced Blood Main don't revert Dragonborn, Dawnguard or etc. patches (added to blocklist)
	Hunterborn Arrows will now act right.
	Assorted other things.

Changes:
	Mace of Molag Bal changed to use Spiked Mace weapon type.
	Updated enchantment description on several armors (expects Mage module to be used), added CCF keywords to Wintermyst armors. (Clothing and Clutter Fixes)
	Some items adjusted to match new WAFR v5.1 stats.

Additions:
	Updated for More Interesting Loot v5.2
	Added new Materials Zero_Daedric, Zero_Dragonplate, Zero_Dragonscale and Dragonscale_One.
	Added recipes to craft Leather from Leather Strips at the Tanning Rack.
	Additional Vilja bindings and adjustments.
	Dawnbreaker can no longer be Reforged or Warforged.
	Added a few missing CCOR armors

Balancing:
	Reduced Armor value of Dragonscale material by 1.
	Increased Longbow damage by 16%
	Increased Longbow critical damage from 150% to 170%
	Increased severity of Broken modifier from 50% to 25%
	Increased bonus speed for WOOD weapons by 1% per rank
	Increased Light Weapons base damage by 1.
	Increased Arrow base damage by 3.
	Increased Bolt base damage by 2.

Renamed:
	Ebony Mail -> Ebony Light Mail (CCOR)
	Miraak -> Miraak Light (WAFR)
	Several enchanted Imperial Bracers of XX -> Imperial Light Bracers of XX (WAFR)
	Blessed Steel Crossbow -> Steel Crossbow of Dismissal (WAFR)
	Enhanced Steel Crossbow -> Steel Enhanced Crossbow (WAFR)
	Steel Bastard Sword -> Steel Longsword (CCOR)

Updated Patches:
	Pre PaMa WAFR Patch
	Pre PaMa CCOR Patch
	Pre PaMa CCF Patch (now requires "Dawnguard.esm" and "PerMa Expansion 1 - Wintermyst.esp").

New Patches:
	PerMa_USKP master patch.esp (will install by default, load immediately after Thief module or merge the change into the Thief module. File only makes one (1) edit to NPC Vex to carry over updated USKP package data.
</v2.3>
<v2.2>
Now covers:
	Bosmer Armor (37289) v1.3
	Warrior Within Weapons (42280) v1
	Vindskjaer (59525)
	Vampiric Thirst (24222)
	EotW Dovahkiins Journeyman Armor (44592)
	Forgotten Magic Redone (35339) v1.6.5
	OBIS Loot (52067) v3

Blocklist:
	NordicCooking.esp
	HorseCloakCH.esp
	HorseCloak.esp
	Post_PatchusMaximus_GiantsAIFix.esp
	Post PatchusMaximus Perma Mods and Tweaks.esp
	LongerDurationsandAnnoyanceFixes - Perma Patch.esp
	zzEstrus.esp

Fixes:
	Corrected bindings for Vindskjær/Vindskjaer Bow. (Nock to Tip/Vindskjaer)

Changes:
	Removed description from "Enhanced Steel Crossbow" to come in-line with USKP and WAFR changes.
	Immersive Weapons LLs adjusted to match WAFR, stops Orcish weapons from appearing at level 6.

Balancing:
	Reduced base rating of "common" Imperial and Stormcloak armor.

Renamed:
	Vanilla 'Steel Scimitar' renamed 'Heavy Steel Scimitar' to differentiate it from the one added by PerMa. (WAFR/CCOR)

Updated Patches:
	Better Vampires: Added clothing keyword to 'Steel Plate Boots'.
	Reduced value of 'Steel Scimitar' from 275 to 45 to compensate for it now being more common. (WAFR)
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR IW Patch.esp removed.
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR IW BoYD Patch.esp removed
	Immersive Armors replacement esp, sorted masters.

New Patches:
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR BoYD Patch.esp
	Immersive Weapons.esp (Requires USKP)(WeaponsArmorFixes_ImmersiveWeapons_Patch.esp is merged in)
	lilithssickle_PerMa_Patch.esp
</v2.2>
<v2.1.1>
Now covers:
	Dynamic Loot (42662) (Has some duplicate item names, Last Hope and Flamebreaker,)
	Merta (60195)
	Liliths Sickle - Custom Scythe (22368)
	LustDesign - Dovahkiin Mercenary Gear - CBBE v3 - UNP (15804)
	Warglaives and Silverlight Armor 099 CBBE (10251)
	Elvensniper CBBE Bodyslide Support Conversion (52102)
	HDT Capes (59700)
	SkyRe Races and Standing Stones modules

Exclusions:
	Excluded Bone, Stone, Iron and Steel Hunterborn Knives from being distributed.

Fixes:
	Corrected bindings for "Tribunal Robes and Masks"
	Bow of the DarkOne will now be marked as a shortbow, not a dagger (SoT)
	Improved/New settings for Conan Age of Hyboria Items.

Changes:
	Changed 'Ravenbrand Sword' from Arming Sword to Longsword. (Warzones)
	Made Aela's armors Light and improved exclusions for it.
	Reduced Pickaxe damage and increased crit slightly.
	Reduced Hatchet damage and crit slightly.

Additions:
	Added new Weapon Type binding 'War Axe' to stop items from being named "Steel War Axe [Waraxe]", Axe and Waraxe items will still have [Waraxe] appended.
	Added missing Ahzidal and Zahkriisos Dragon Priest Mask exclusions.

Balancing:
	Increased Heavy Weapons damage by 30%.
	Increased Ranged Weapons damage by 15%.
	Increased Light Weapons damage by 1.
	Reduced severity of 'heavy' modifier.
</v2.1.1>
<v2.1.0>
Now covers:
	Dovamaar and Dovahfaas (51842)
	Blood Witch Armor (21572)
	Raven witch armor (36497)
	Medusa Drakul armors and Thanatos dragon (31229)
	skyrim monster mod (35631)

Exclusions:
	Gwelda and Emfy armors will no longer be distributed or have random enchanted versions made, since they are Female only items.
	Aditional "Horripilation" exclusion.
	

Blocklist:
	Spectraverse - Only After Dragon Rising.esp

Fixes:

Changes:
	Corrected Nettlebane distribution exclusion to actually block it from being distributed.
	Slightly increased DaedricLight armor rating to match Dragonscale as intended.
	Increased base armor of Dragonpriest Masks slightly and adjusted their materials to better match how they look.

Additions:
	Ahzidal, Dukaan and Zahkriisos Dragonpriest masks.

Balancing:
	Adjusted weapon_type base damage for new formula added in PerMa 1.1

Renamed:

Updated Patches:
	Included voxatu's updated Pre PaMa Improved Artifacts.esp

New Patches:
</v2.1.0>
<v2.0.2>
Now covers:
	Advanced Skyrim Overhaul (aka Nature of the beast II) (20721)
	Latex Corset - CBBE TBBP with BODYSLIDE (49350)
	Ancient Nord Chainmail CBBE HDT (26664)
	TERA Armor Collection - CBBE - standalone (29411)
	Emfy Cleric Robes UNP - CBBE (61013)
	Gwelda Armor Pack UNP (56998)
	Expanded Winterhold Destruction Ruins (8333)
	Nameless Light by FavoredSoul (59254) was already supported but never mentioned as such.
	Jester Outfit ReTexture -Standalone and Craftable (17530)
	Witch of the Wild (38164)
	Imperial Investigator Armor UNP - UNPB (19377)
	Seratic armor (19961)
	Royal Daedric and Daedra Huntress armors (3104)
	Male Cleric Armor Variants (14194)
	Craftable Cleric *Heavy Version* (3214)
	Contractor and Mavari armors (38386)

Exclusions:
	Nameless Light will no longer be distributed. (Nameless Light)
	Frostfall weapons will no longer be enchanted or distributed.
	Dragon Priest Masks can no longer be reforged or Warforged.
	Unenchanted Archmage armors will no longer be distributed.

Blocklist:
	Spectraverse
	Dwemertech
	
Fixes/Changes:
	Aemer's Mahakaman Blade will now be a Greatsword (Aemer's Refuge)
	Corrected a typo on Ulcissor Armor (TERA) has both Ulciscor and Ulcissor now.
	Corrected Penetus Oculatus to Light Armor.
</v2.0.2>
<v2.0.1>
Now covers:
	Nightmare Armor by Hentai (13667)
	Aemer's Refuge (37450)

Blocklist:
	Added Ish's Respec Mod.esp to blocklist

Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected typo in Ammunition.xml that prevented most ammunition from correctly having variants made.

Balancing:
	Reduced Glass Arrow/Bolt damage from +12 to +10 as I meant to in 1.8.

</v2.0.1>
<v2.0.0>
Now covers:
	 Castle Valdmire (55215)
	 Unique scimitars (Hammerfell armoury) (60896)

Exclusions:
	More exclusions for Ilas-Tei's Ring
	Fork of Horripilation will no longer be distributed.

Blocklist:
	Added HDTPhysicsWeaponSling.esp to Blocklist.
	kuertee's Eat and sleep added to Blocklist
Fixes/Changes:
	Weapon Base Damage Formula changed from:
		(int) ((skillBase + typeMod + matMod) * typeMult) * [modifiers]
	to:
		(int) (skillBase + typeMod*matMod) * [modifiers]
	Corrected a typo in Vilja enchanted weapon distribution exclusion setting.
	Improved 'Lustmord' Armor support.
	Corrected a typo in Hunterborn weapon distribution exclusions.
	Justiciar Changdao and Nordic Dwemer Blade will now patch correctly (IW)
	Trident Blade changed from Shortspear to Shortsword to better match visual.

Additions:
	Updated Alchemy.xml to v17.
	Added 'Low' material bindings for most materials, don't expect to actually use them all, but they are there now.
	Added 'DaedricArtifact' material bindings to fill a few odd gaps in Artifact damage. (Not fully implemented.)

Balancing:
	Adjusted all Weapon Material and Type Damage ratings for new formula.
	Changed Claw weapon crit from 2.0 to 0.75.
	Changed Katar weapons speed  from 1.2 to 1.3 and crit from 1.75 to 1.5.
	Changed Knuckle weapon speed from 1.45 to 1.3 and crit from 2.0 to 0.5.
	Changed Katar from Bladed to Piercing
	Changed Claw from Piercing to Blade.
	Claw, Katar and Knuckle damage increased from 1 to 1.25.

Updated Patches:
	WAFR (Carried over USKP/PerMa 1.1 name changes to several armors.)
	CCOR BOYD (carried over CCOR weapon LLI on NPC Majhad)
	Immersive Armors (Removed Object Manager Data)
	Wind Destruction Magic (Most PerMa perks now innately cover Wind magic. Removed Whirlwind Cloak since PerMa adds a new version. Corrected conditions in Unified perk that caused elemental spell damage to not increase when a contract perk was taken, example; Taking Pyromancer Contract caused non-Fire spell damage to increase for each wind perk not taken.)

</v2.0.0>
<v1.8>
Now covers:
	True Bound Daedric Armors (34269)
	WARZONES 2015 - Civil Unrest (9494)
	SPOA Silver Knight Armor (32275) and Shield (34496)
	Ghosus Weapon Pack (28545)
	Armonizer (27028)
	Weaponizer (24015)
	Weapon Variants Expansion (10902)
	Bosmer Armour Pack (37289)
	Scout Armor (7109)
	Grace Darklings Elven Scout Armor (35174)

Exclusions:
	Heartwood Bow will no longer be distributed. (Hunterborn)
	Armor of the Old Gods set will no longer be distributed.
	'Woodcutter' and 'Pickaxe' will no longer be distributed, or have enchanted versions made.
	CCOR 'ArmoredCirclet's will no longer have Reforged, Warforged versions made. Will add them to the CCOR patch in PCaPP v2.
	CCOR 'ArmoredCirclet's will no longer have Quality versions made. (PerMa v1.1) Will add them to the CCOR patch in PCaPP v2.
	Distribution and Enchanting exclusions for Unique Bows Collection (32405).

Blocklist:
	Dual Sheath Redux Patch.esp and Dual Sheath Redux.esp added to Blocklist.

Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected a typo that prevented 'Nordic Ranger' Armors from patching correctly.
	Corrected a typo that prevented 'Wild Hunt' Heavy Armors from patching correctly.
	Corrected typos on 'Viator' 'Blade Dancer' and 'Moon Buckled' that prevented proper patching. (TERA)
	Improved Vilja (26393) settings

Additions:
	Added 'Sylward' entry for TERA.
	Added new Material and Type explicitly for Giant weapons, Giant Club base damage increased from 23 to 64, swing speed reduced from 0.85 to 0.8. Weapon Sagger and Debuff tier increased to 3, Bleed decreased to 2. Range increased for 1.2 to 1.3. Crit reduced to 0.5. Now uses Longmace archetype instead of Greatsword.
	

Balancing:
	Adjusted a modifier that were causing Lightweight Crossbow variants to have erroneous values.
	Increased Shortspear crit from 08 -> 1.5.
	Increased Hunting Knife crit from 0.5 -> 1.2
	Increased Halberd crit from 0.3 -> 0.8
	Reduced Club crit from 0.7 -> 0.3 to match Mace
	Reduced Katar crit from 2.5 -> 1.75
	Reduced Battlestaff crit from 0.9 -> 0.5
	Reduced Shortbow crit from 1.5 -> 1.3
	Reduced Shortbow speed from 1.2 -> 1.0
	Increased Crossbow crit from 1.0 -> 1.5
	Increased Longbow crit from 0.9 -> 1.5
	Increased Longbow speed from 0.4 -> 0.6
	Increased Arming Sword, Broadsword and Waraxe crit from 0.5 -> 0.8
	Increased Broadsword damage from 6.0 -> 7.0
	Reduced Broadsword speed from 1.0 -> 0.9
	Elven, Nordic, Glass, Dragonbone Arrow/Bolt damage increased.
	Falmer, Iron, Steel, Silver, Dwarven, Stalhrim Arrow/Bolt damage decreased.
	Corrected a typo that caused Orcish weapons to be 6% faster instead of 6% slower.

Updated Patches:
	Wind Destruction Magic (Changes in included Readme)
	Bound Armory Patch (Visuals)
	WAFR (Keywords on Nordic items to get them sorted right.)
	CCOR (Removed duplicate PerMa Longbow recipe)
	Pre PaMa Improved Artifacts.esp (Removed duplicate ArmorNightingale keyword from both Nightingale Hood armors.)

New Patches:
	AetheriumSwordsnArmor.esp (Replacer)
	Nock2Tip.esp (Replacer)
</v1.8>
<v1.7>
Now covers:
	Scoiatael Weapons (18439)
	Nicoroshi Creations (15122)
	Ghorzas Armor (36459)
	Helgen Reborn (35841)
	Faction: Pitfighter
	Faction: Pitfighter Travels
	Nock to Tip (60219)
	Bound Armory (45042)
	True Bound Armors (30462)
	Hadhafang - Arwens Sword - LOTR (8456)
	Ghosu - Horker Weapon pack (48557)

Exclusions:
	Can no longer reforge Pickaxe or Woodcutters axe's

Fixes/Changes:
	Updated merged patch info in the installer. Made installer a bit (lot) neater.
	Corrected stray Yari bindings to use the correct Partisan binding.
	Fixed 3DNPC/Interesting NPCs for real. For really real! (or as best as can be.)
	Corrected an error where Nordic weapons required the steel perk, steel ingots to temper, and brakedown to steel ingots. Will now require the Advanced perk and Corundum.

Additions:
	Spanish translation finished.
	Bindings for Bound ammunition.

Balancing:
	Reduced severity of Ancient modifier from -20% damage to -10% damage.

Renamed:
	Horker XX I  -> Horker XX (Horker Weapon pack)
	Horker XX II -> Horker Honed XX (Horker Weapon pack)

New Patches:
	Pre PaMa Bound Armory Patch - Place after WAFR patch.
	Pre PaMa LeftHandRings WAFR Patch
	Left Hand Rings Merged containing LeftHandRings.esp, LeftHandRings - Dawnguard.esp and Left Hand Rings WAFR Patch
	Winter is Coming replacement esp
	Ghosu - Horker Weapon pack replacement esp
</v1.7>
<v1.6.1>
Now covers:
	Ygrayne (60066)
	Gorehowl (50123)
	R18Pn - Eisen Platte Armor (11050)

Exclusions:
	Excluded 'Backpack' from having a Reforged recipe made.
	Excluded distribution of Chillrend, Dawnbreaker, Dark Brotherhood, Ghostblade, Mehrunes Razor, Mace of Molag Bal, Ebony Blade, Zephyr, Gloves of the Pugilist, Ebony Mail, Masque of Clavicus Vile, Aetherial Shield, Archmage, Muiri's Ring, Nightweaver's Band, Shield of Ysgramor, Saarthal Amulet, MG02, MG05, MG07, DA0, DA1, Spellbreaker and Savos Aren's Amulet.
	Improved Gauldur and Aela's Shield distribution exclusions.

Blocklist:
	Additional Blocklist entries from Crush.
	
Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected Dragonscale armor scaling, DragonscaleLow/High will now have armor rating just below/above standard Dragonscale.
	Removed the Ring keyword from Barbarian Hero Bracers that prevented them from having a Reforged recipe created.
	Adjusted all Armingsword bindings to Arming Sword for consistency and correctness.
	Corrected Dwarven Mage Heavy set. (Immersive Armors)
	Corrected Goblin Bindings (SiC)

Additions:
	Full German translation support.
	Added armor binding for 'Light Blades'
	Alchemy 16 - fix an issue with More Interesting Loot.

Balancing:
	Reduced base crit damage of Dagger/Tanto/Shiv
	Reduced severity of 'Old' modifier from -20% armor rating to -5% and added matching 'Old' modifier to weapons.

Renamed:
	Updated WAFR patches to properly rename 'Crossbow' to 'Steel Crossbow' and 'Enhanced Crossbow' to 'Enhanced Steel Crossbow'.

Updated Patches:
	All WAFR patches
	Immersive Armors Patches - PerMa_SkyRe_No More Duplicate Immersive Weapons Breakdown Recipes (60228) merged in.

New Patches:
	Pre PaMa SiC Patch -Names Patch for a few Goblin Shields and adds Clothing keyword to a few skins to stop PaMa from patching them.
</v1.6.1>
<v1.5>
Now covers:
	Morrowloot 4E (50740)

Exclusions:
	Additional DLC Spell and Book exclusions.
	Additional Wyrmstooth Spell and Book exclusions.
	Arise - Black Sacrament Armor Crafting Books and Spells will no longer be passed out.
	Additional Interesting NPCs Weapon and Armor exclusions.
	Additional Improved Artifacts Collection Weapon and Armor exclusions.

Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected a few Warmonger bindings.
	Corrected a few Improved Artifacts Collection bindings.
	Adjusted all Arming Sword bindings to Armingsword for consistency. Arming Sword will still bind as Arming Sword.
	Corrected Broadsword and Armingsword bindings.
	Corrected a few 3DNPC/Interesting NPCs bindings.
	Corrected a few Inconsequential NPCs bindings.
	

Additions:

Balancing:
	Reduced Hatchet reach from 0.95 to 0.7
	Increased Hatchet damage from 2 to 3
	Increased Hatchet speed from 0.95 to 1.1
	Increased Hatchet Crit from 0.1 to 0.4
	Reduced Waraxe speed from 0.95 to 0.9
	Changed 'Hero' modifier to 'Heroes'

Renamed:

New Patches:
	Pre PaMa Improved Artifacts WAFR USKP Hearthfires Patch 
</v1.5>
<v1.4>
Now covers:
	Aetherium Arms and Armor (23530)
	Blackreach Railroad
	Brhuce: Legacy
	Aethernautics
	Lost wonder of Mzark
	Midas Magic in Skyrim - fixed (44197)
	Silver Arrows and Bolts (56679)
	The Azincourt (39355)
	The Glimmer (36535)
	Cyrodilic Dagger (43137)
	aMidianborn - Content Addon (24909)
	The Huntsman

Exclusions:
	Added additional distribution exclusions for Wuuthrad, Valdr's Lucky Dagger, The Rueful Axe and The Longhammer.
	Added distribution exclusions for Transmute Mineral Ore Spell and Tome.
	Added an exclusion for any Spell or Spell Tome with "Teleport" in the name.

Fixes/Changes:
	Huntsman's Bow set to Longbow
	Corrected Bindings for aMidianborn - Content Addon

Additions:
	Replaced Uncapper.ini with version updated by Crushboss.

Balancing:
	Reduced 'Alduin' modifier from +30% armor to +10%
	Bindings for Silver Arrows and Bolts with damage equal to Steel.
	Bindings for Skyforge Steel Arrows and Bolts with damage slightly above Steel.
	Increased LightIron armor binding from 10 to 14
	Increased LightSteel armor binding from 12 to 16
	Increased LightBonemold armor binding from 14 to 18

Renamed:
	Falkreath Armor -> Falkreath Thane (IA patch), can now be properly bound as Heavy Armor.

New Patches:
	Frostfall patch to adjust spell costs, more to come with this.
</v1.4>
<v1.3>
Now covers:
	Apocalypse
	Spectraverse
	Dwemertech
	Thunderchild
	Vilja (26393)
	Tera Armors (25846)

Exclusions:
	Improved distribution exclusions for Apocalypse, Spectraverse, Dwemertech and Thunderchild.
	'The Longhammer' will no longer be distributed.
	Unique/Quest items covered by Unique Uniques will no longer be distributed.
	Blocked spells from Sands of Time, Cutting Room Floor and Vanilla spells from being passed out.
	Added a temporary distribution exclusion for any spell with an _ (Underscore) in the EDID.

Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected typo that prevented Ornate Wood Bow from patching. (Archer's Armory)
	Base costs fixed for: Weakness to Fire, Frost, Shock and Ravage Health.

Additions:
	Added missing settings so PaMa will no longer pass out Apoc, Spectraverse, Dwemertech or Thunderchild Books, Spells, Armor, Weapons or add anything to their Leveled Item lists.
	Added entries for Vilja's custom armor and Food/Ingrediants.

Balancing:
	Increased stats of all Lore Weapon Expansion weapons by 10%
	Reduced faction armor Armor Rating a bit (Includes Imperials and Stormcloaks).
	Removed a modifier that was causing the Penitus set to have an overly high armor rating.
	Reduced severity of many modifiers.
</v1.3>
<v1.2>
Now covers:
	Spectraverse
	Dwemertech
	Lore Weapon Expansion

Exclusions:
	Added The Woodsman's Friend to LL exclusions, it will nolonger be found as random loot.
	Added The Woodsman's Friend to enchanting exclusions, it will have random enchanted versions.
	Spectraverse and Dwemertech Spell Tomes will nolonger be found as random loot.

Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected BASH tag settings in file descriptions, Wrye should auto detect them now as intended.
	Corrected all errors in all patches.
	Added 'Custom bindings' section to Armor.xml and Weapons.xml.
	Corrected the Wood weapon binding, should correctly catch them all.
	Corrected The Woodsman's Friend type binding, it will now be a Battleaxe, not a Hatchet.

Additions:
	Added IronLow weapon material, will add 'Low' of other materials over time.

New Patches:
	Archer's Armory - Lore Weapon Expansion
	Archer's Armory
	
</v1.2>
<v1.1.1>
Fixes/Changes:
	Corrected format error in installer that made NMM mad.
	Corrected Lustmord Vampire Armor to be Light Armor.

</v1.1.1>
<v1.1>
Fixes/Changes:
	Added CrimsonTwilight binding to catch misnamed gauntlets and Coat. (Crimson Twilight Armor)
	BOYD patch now covers NPC Razhinda (conflict with PerMa Thief plugin)
	CCOR patch now covers Necromancer Amulet (conflict with PerMa Mage plugin)
	Fixed Hunterborn arrows. (for real, see I wrote it down this time!)
	Fix CCOR patch
	Fixed Falskaar's 'Vanvir's Masterpiece' quest weapon item from having enchanted versions made and passed out, which could break a Falskaar quest.
	Fixed a keyword count error in WAFR patch that could cause patcher to fail.
	Corrected a typo in the installer, had BoYD_ESF patch named as BoYD_EFF patch.

Additions:
	Added additional support for German, Spanish, French, Russian, Greek, Polish and Ukrainian languages.
	Restricted distribution of spells and books for Flying Mod Beta, Lustmord Vampire Armor and Immersive Wenches. 

New Patches:
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR IW BoYD Patch
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR IW Patch
	Pre PaMa WAFR CCOR Patch
	Pre PaMa WAFR IW Patch

</v1.1>
<v1>
http://pastebin.com/bmwJ5fqd - Pre Release history
</v1>
</Old>
</Versions>
